[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 12]
I apologize to everyone.
I won't disturb you anymore.
Qingyuan!
Chunzhi, listen to me.
I've heard enough from you!
Chunzhi!
You give her your whole heart,
but you don't even know
she's leading you on
while fooling around with Yan Rui
behind your back!
Stop making a scene.
I'm not!
Chunzhi,
do you know
Grandmother has already
betrothed her to Yan Rui?
Utter nonsense!
This is unseemly!
Mother...
Qingyuan!
Qingyuan.
What Qingru just said,
don't take it to heart.
She's always been
spoiled like that.
I'll find a time to have a serious
word with her.
You saw the spectacle
that unfolded just now.
I'm seen as the black sheep
of the Xie family.
If you're looking to get married,
you should choose someone fitting.
I don't care what others say.
My previous rash proposal
was forced by the situation.
But instead of evading it,
you treated me with sincerity.
That made me
respect you even more.
You're really
good at comforting people.
I feel much better now.
I just wonder
which lucky gentleman will
get to marry you.
There are things I have to do.
When I'm done with them,
I'll leave marriage to fate.
Does that mean...
there's no one in your heart right now?
I'm not looking for love.
But there's one thing
I need your help with.
Sure. What is it?
I want to see the marquis.
My father?
I know he rarely sees outsiders,
but I have an urgent matter.
I can't tell you why right now,
but I promise
I'll explain everything later.
Okay.
I will make it happen.
Thank you.
Are you out of your mind?
You must be possessed,
acting crazy in front of
the marquis's son!
Is this how I raised you?
Qingyuan has
long belonged to Yan Rui,
yet she still goes out of her way
to seduce my Chunzhi.
I was worried Chunzhi would be fooled.
That's why I told him.
She's the one
who did those shameful things.
Mother,
why are you scolding me?
How dare you talk back!
Mother,
stop scolding Second Sister.
She didn't do anything wrong.
Shut up.
If I don't
discipline you properly today,
who knows
what kind of trouble
you might cause down the line?
Nanny Liu.
Punish her with
20 lashes of the cane!
Mother!
Yes.
Hit her!
Go on!
Mother, just beat me to death!
Hit me!
These can go on the shelves.
Okay.
It's rare to see you so lost in thought.
Are you thinking of
Young Master Li or Lord Yan?
Of course I'm thinking of...
you, Eldest Sister.
Do you think marriage is
some kind of joke?
Right now, be it
Young Master Li or Lord Yan,
you have to make a choice.
Young Master Li
comes from a prominent family
and has a pure heart.
He won't marry anyone but you.
What's holding you back?
He and I are on different paths.
What about Lord Yan?
Are you on the same path?
Yan Rui is an old fox.
I can't figure him out at all.
You got involved with Lord Yan
because of that estate incident.
Grandmother had no choice.
Now that Father's back,
you should pull out to protect yourself.
He's been driving up grain prices
and swindling army provisions
throughout Hengtang.
He'll run into trouble sooner or later.
I'll get back to work.
The porridge is so watery.
How can we eat it?
You pervert the law!
Corrupt official!
How dare you, you unruly pleb!
Arrest him!
What are you doing?
Let me go!
Corrupt official!
Please don't be mad, My Lord.
Let me go!
My Lord,
to be honest,
these displaced victims
survive on this little relief grain
day after day.
They're at their breaking point.
The county office is also
running out of grain.
I didn't expect there to be
so many disaster victims.
Yes, indeed.
No doubt, the grain is insufficient.
We need to collect more.
My Lord,
if we collect more,
the grain price will likely go up again.
It's even better if it goes up.
Hengtang's been hit so hard
by this disaster;
the relief grain is nowhere near enough.
We'll have to collect sooner or later.
Think about it, Lord Wei.
As long as we have the grain,
the higher the price,
the higher we can sell it
to the imperial court.
Both inside and out,
there's a lot of money to be made here.
You're absolutely right, My Lord.
But there is one thing I don't get.
Where should we get the money
for collecting grain?
The imperial court.
The relief silver allocated by the court
is on the way.
When the time comes,
we'll split the grain
and the money equally.
The grain is in our hands,
and so is the money.
Please forgive my slow brain.
That's why you've been checking
the army provisions everywhere
since you arrived in Hengtang.
Your Lordship
is truly a brilliant strategist
with great foresight.
So, Lord Wei,
please pay extra attention
to the relief grain.
It's an honor to share your burdens.
I'd gladly lay down my life
for you, My Lord!
Good.
By the way,
I've decided that the grain collection
will be on the eighth of next month.
Noted.
Take care, My Lord.
That's a risky move you're making.
Holding out
until the supplies come is easy.
The hard part is keeping control
and dealing with
their inevitable retaliation.
It is risky.
So we must have enough troops
to ensure that nothing goes wrong.
Where will you get the troops?
You mean,
after the case was concluded,
Yan Rui hasn't made any moves?
That's right, My Lord.
Please have a look at
this bowl of Purple Bamboo Shoot Tea
I've whisked.
Isn't it vibrant and aromatic?
No wonder the Tea Sage, Lu Yu, called it
the crown jewel of all teas.
Please enjoy, My Lord.
It's only been a few days,
and you've suddenly become so cultured.
Well, your sudden visit
couldn't be just to
whisk a bowl of tea for me.
You're mistaken, My Lord.
In just a few days since you got back,
you've made Yan Rui
move out of the Xie Residence
and drop the grain swap investigation.
What absolute genius
and incredible foresight.
This bowl isn't just tea.
It is a show of my
admiration and respect for you.
Elegance cannot be learned.
Do you know this tea has another name
called Jicheng?
"Ji" as in "urgent,"
and "cheng" as in "journey."
It means
this tea is very urgent.
Since the tea leaves leave the tea tree,
every extra moment of delay
reduces its freshness.
So, while you appear to be
elegantly whisking the tea
at your own pace,
you are, in fact, ruining it.
You seem to be
implying something.
I'm dull-witted.
Please speak plainly.
I wouldn't dare.
I just think
things are
in reverse.
All thanks to your care,
my son survived this disaster.
I should be the one toasting you
with this bowl of tea.
My dear lord,
everything I've done was
purely for the agenda
of the person who pulls the strings.
Second Young Master aside,
you and I are like fish in this water.
If one fish suffers,
the whole school perishes.
It's not enough that
you ruined the good tea.
Now you're harming my fish.
Let's get down to business.
The grain swap matter,
I've settled it for you.
But Yan Rui is too unpredictable
[Ledger]
[1st Month of the 8th Year of Jingxi]
[Ledger] [20 grain-transport boats;
3,000 dan collected]
a person.
If he stirs up trouble again,
you'd better hold onto your sedan chair.
I can't help with everything.
[7 water ships borrowed from the Xies,
not officially registered]
Have you forgotten?
Who granted me this sedan chair,
and who is carrying it for me?
Ultimately,
Yan Rui is still after fame and fortune.
He wants to use disaster relief
as an excuse
to earn political merit
and then make a windfall.
In that case,
we should play along
and help him secure the grain.
Once the money and grain are in our hands,
we can eliminate him
without getting
our hands dirty.
Then we'll submit a petition
to His Majesty against him,
pushing all the blame
onto him alone.
By then,
My Lord,
you and I will
both be worry-free.
Where'd we get so much grain?
Looks like
we'll have to put on a good show.
Yum!
It's delicious.
This plum blossom pastry
not only nourishes the skin
and enhances beauty
but also really smells like plum blossoms.
This four-herb lotus seed cake
is also quite exquisite.
Its subtle, pleasant sweetness perfectly
complements its therapeutic benefits of
soothing the mind,
strengthening the spleen,
and dispelling body dampness.
Have a taste.
Sure.
I hope our herbal snacks
will be crowd-pleasers,
so our efforts won't be in vain.
Don't worry, Qingyuan.
Such tasty snacks will
definitely sell well.
They're so good.
Good thing we're opening a shop.
Otherwise,
I'd polish off everything.
-Have some more.
-My Lady.
A guest outside
wants to see you.
Army Inspector of the Northern Frontier,
I, the fourth daughter
of the Hengtang Xie family,
pay my respects to Your Lordship.
So you are the Fourth Lady,
Xie Qingyuan.
Since you know my name,
you must be no stranger to the Xie family.
Grandmother gave us this shop
to practice with.
I stayed a bit late today.
Since we're fated to meet,
why don't you
come in and try our snacks?
My son insists on marrying you.
So I came
specially to see
what kind of woman you are.
You're easy on the eyes,
but not particularly special.
I'm curious.
You're a lady of noble birth,
yet you show your face in the streets
and engage in petty commerce.
What kind of spell
did you put on my son?
My Lord,
if you're visiting our snack shop
for tea and snacks,
please deign to step out of your sedan
and come in to taste them.
We will host you well.
If you're only here to act superior
and heap scorn and insult on me,
then I'm sorry,
but our measly shop
is too insignificant
to host a distinguished guest like you.
Sharp-tongued
philistine.
A marriage between you and my son
is absolutely blasphemous.
Let's head home.
Take care, My Lord.
Qingyuan,
that was the Marquis of Danyang.
He wields massive military power
and has a twisted personality.
Why'd you provoke him?
I can't worry about that right now.
I need you to do me a favor.
Let's eat.
Congxin.
Congxin!
Alright. Come on.
There are tons of great ladies around.
Why fixate on one woman?
Isn't Qingru a catch too?
And you.
How could you be so mean
to the woman our son likes?
My Lady—
Your fuse is getting shorter and shorter.
My Lady!
When you came begging my family
for my hand in marriage
when you were younger,
weren't you just like this?
Is it really that difficult to
put yourself in our boy's shoes?
-My Lady.
-Be more understanding.
No matter what,
that woman cannot
cross the threshold of our household.
I'm done eating.
I'm full too.
You father and son are unbelievable!
One is more stubborn than the other!
I'm done eating too!
Who needs a family
like this anyway!
My Lord.
Young Master.
Madam.
Miss Qingyuan had someone
bring a box of herbal snacks.
How exquisite.
She's so thoughtful.
It's delicious.
My Lord,
they're really well made.
Count me out.
Come here.
Come on. Try it.
It's hot.
Delicious, right?
Mm, yes. Delicious.
I knew
you must still be thinking of me.
How about
the two of you
meet each other halfway?
My Lady,
I'm fine.
That's better.
Don't just look at it.
Eat up.
It's delicious.
By the way, Madam,
Miss Qingyuan also said
these snacks are an apology
to the marquis.
What a sweet girl.
Grandmother.
Let me have a taste.
Mother.
So pretty.
Really good.
Delicious.
Sweet but not cloying,
soft and tasty,
and even good for your health.
Qingyuan's shop will
surely be a success.
Opening this shop
is a good thing,
but Qingyuan is not yet married.
Doing everything herself
must be exhausting.
Constantly being in the public eye
will inevitably invite gossip.
Why not get someone in the residence
to manage it for you
and share your burden?
It wasn't easy for Qingyuan
to get this shop
up and running.
Of course it wasn't easy.
Regardless, it's still
inappropriate for a lady
to always show her face
in public.
What is more crucial for a lady
than a blessed and smooth marriage?
Alright.
The girl is grown up
and has her own ideas.
Let her do what she wants to do.
It's not as if
a lady from the Xie family...
would ever struggle to find a husband.
Mother,
you're spoiling Qingyuan too much.
I actually think our household
is doing much better than before.
In terms of management,
you should learn from Mei Yinghua.
You're right, Mother.
I have a lot to learn.
I'll look to seek advice
from Concubine Mei.
But Mother,
because of Zhengjun's matter,
the Xie family was besieged,
causing quite a stir outside.
Although the incident has passed,
I can't help...
but feel sorry for Eldest Lady.
Not one person from
the Founding Count's household
has shown up since.
It wouldn't look good
if word got out that she is
working in the shop.
The Founding Count's household
values Eldest Sister.
Preparing for
a perfect wedding
naturally takes time.
Fret not about my little shop,
First Madam.
You're busy as it is,
what with all the household affairs.
Sure.
As long as you know what you're doing.
I trust that you will
evaluate the priorities
and make mindful choices.
Your shop is a small matter...
but your eldest sister's marriage
is a big deal.
Enough talk.
Let's all taste what Qingyuan made.
Qingyuan,
since you've decided on it,
commit and do it well.
I understand.
Dear locals and distinguished guests,
[Yunji Snacks]
our Yunji Snacks
is officially open!
Our original snacks are
uniquely handcrafted
by combining
traditional Chinese herbal formulas
[Cherokee Rosehip & Jade Dew Ball]
[Coix Seed & Poria Cake]
with various culinary techniques.
With 36 distinct herbal snacks,
there's surely something for everyone.
Next,
please follow me into the shop
to make your pick.
So many kinds!
I didn't expect our herbal snacks
to be so popular.
It's a pity that we're both unmarried
and have to miss out on the fun.
What kind of pointless rule is that?
If you want to go,
I'll go with you.
Madam Pei has arrived!
Contrary to Concubine Lian's worries
that Madam Pei would
waver about your marriage
because Xie Residence was besieged,
Madam Pei has come here in person.
But why are you hiding instead?
I'm not ready yet.
Are you afraid that Madam Pei
is here to break off the engagement?
I doubt that's the case.
To break off the engagement,
a letter would be enough.
Madam Pei coming here in person
means that things have
taken a turn for the better.
Don't be scared.
I'll go with you.
How ingenious of
the women of the Xie family
to come up with such a brilliant idea.
Madam Pei.
Let's go.
The business is booming, huh?
I almost couldn't spot you.
Greetings, Madam Pei.
Madam Pei,
long time no see.
Come,
let me have a look at you.
My wonderful daughter-in-law.
It's been a while, and you've
become even more beautiful.
Come,
shop with me.
Let's pick some snacks.
We're going to be family soon.
Don't be so formal around me.
Got it, Madam Pei.
You know what?
Your business sure is booming.
Why are you here?
It's your opening day.
How could I not come and show support?
Is my tiny shop
befitting of your attention?
With your financial power,
you could buy out my shop in a flash.
You're getting sweeter and sweeter
with your words.
I wonder if Young Master Li knows.
If you want to ask about the progress
of the task you gave me,
just get to the point.
Why beat around the bush?
I see.
Judging from your reaction,
I take it the task
hasn't been completed yet.
What,
are you going to make me
wait until you and Young Master Li
have a child?
Qingyuan!
Qingyuan.
Young Master Li.
Chunzhi heard that you opened today.
He insisted on coming,
saying that not even the end of times
could stop him.
Qingyuan,
I'm here to deliver an invitation.
My parents would like to
invite you to watch an opera.
[From the Marquis of Danyang family]
The marquis?
The marquis rarely sees outsiders.
Today he's actually
inviting you to an opera.
Do I hear some wedding bells ringing?
Lord Yan, a lot of free time lately?
You are everywhere.
Of course.
Good thing I'm here,
or I'd have missed out on
this joyous event.
You aren't invited to the opera.
That's not joyous.
However,
when Fourth Lady and I get married,
I can invite you for a drink
and share some of my good luck with you.
Is the banquet already booked?
Why aren't I aware?
Fourth Lady, are you aware of it?
Lord Yan, you don't have to
worry about this.
Fourth Lady's heart and my heart are
perfectly in tune.
Marriage is a major event
decided by one's parents.
Please stop putting my sister on the spot.
Yes,
that's right.
It's not up to me anyway.
Please, Your Lordships,
enough teasing me.
It's Yunji Snacks' opening day.
Pick whatever
you want.
It's on me. How does that sound?
Qingyuan,
can you recommend some snacks for me?
Have a seat.
This is
our notoginseng sticky rice cake.
Notoginseng stops bleeding
and disperses blood stasis.
Sticky rice flushes out toxins
and reduces swelling.
♪ Spring comes to the long gate,
green grass sprouts ♪
♪ Red plums bear dewdrops,
bright and serene ♪
Eldest Brother, you're upright,
and Second Brother
did nothing wrong to get hurt.
Since we're like-minded,
it only makes sense
♪ Year by year, time drifts along ♪
to get closer.
♪ Warmth and chill
of mortal meet and part ♪
Thank you, Qingyuan.
♪ No need to heed the wind's soft whisper
and ask about your return ♪
Chunzhi,
let's go.
We've bought the snacks
and delivered the invitation.
We shouldn't keep Mr. Lanshan waiting.
♪ Wild geese soar through deep clouds,
waiting for the moon to rest ♪
Qingyuan,
see you at the southern opera.
♪ Old memories lie heavy,
haunting every dream ♪
As you saw,
♪ Rises and falls take turns ♪
I've gotten the invitation
from Marquis of Danyang.
Which means I've completed
♪ Phases of the moon,
unplanned to wax and wane ♪
half of what you asked me to do.
Yes,
the task I entrusted to you is half done.
But isn't your blessed big day
halfway here as well?
I'm blessed to be able
to share your burden.
The silly look on your face
really resembles a harmless little rabbit.
Unfortunately,
someone is about to
bark up the wrong tree.
What do you mean by that?
I thought
you were just good at taming horses.
To think you're also
good at taming people.
Even the most capable heroes
couldn't get an audience
with the marquis,
yet you received an invitation
in just a few days.
Don't you think the marquis's son
deserves huge credit?
Strange.
Why do you smell
so sour today?
Did someone
spill vinegar all over you?
I'm just happy.
I'm happy that I, the fox,
didn't capture a little rabbit,
but a veritable immortal
with profound cultivation.
It was just a joke.
The way you reacted,
you might just have
let your true feelings slip.
Since I'm a weapon
who is valuable to you,
shouldn't you take good care of me?
Otherwise, it'll be a pity.
♪ If the wind softly whispers your name ♪
Then you should be careful.
Don't show your true form so soon.
♪ If my heart softly hears your voice ♪
♪ I'm still here,
holding on to our memories ♪
What's wrong?
Are you scared?
♪ Quietly waiting in the passage of time
for a reply ♪
As for what you asked,
I'll get it done
♪ Listening to every word, every line,
everything about you ♪
within 3 days.
Speaking of which, have you fulfilled
my request?
Where is Cui'er?
♪ Your gentle breath,
the traces left by longing ♪
In your big shop, I wonder if
you have my favorite perilla candy.
♪ No sight could ever compare to you,
forever in my heart ♪
You can have
whatever you like.
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become
part of your journey ♪
Hopefully it isn't poisonous this time.
My Lord,
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
have you found Cui'er or not?
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
Alright.
When you fulfill your end of the promise,
I'll take you
to the person you want to see.
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
Goodbye.
Delicious.
Slow down on the snacks.
Do you really think that girl
cares about your recovery?
Mother,
this is quite tasty.
The main thing is that after eating it,
my butt doesn't hurt as much.
[Notoginseng Sticky Rice Cake]
This is an opportunity.
What opportunity?
I could
do First Madam a favor
and have someone
look into Qingyuan's snack shop.
I just don't believe
that you can
polish a turd.
Old Madam.
The Marquis of Danyang household
had a bit of a slip-up.
The invitation meant for our family
wasn't sent to our residence.
Instead, it ended up in Qingyuan's hands.
Fortunately,
the nanny found out early,
so I could get to the bottom of it.
[From the Marquis of Danyang family,
respectfully presented to the Xie family]
Marquis of Danyang's family
never hosts guests.
I don't know whether to celebrate or worry
about this sudden invitation.
[From the Marquis of Danyang family,
respectfully presented to the Xie family]
Mother,
the Marchioness of Danyang is the host,
and their son will be present.
They invited our family's children
and the young ladies.
The opera must be an excuse
to discuss marriage.
It's a cause for celebration.
At my age,
do I need you
to remind me about such things?
Right.
Qingyuan,
tell me the truth.
Do you have feelings for
the marquis's son?
Mother,
I didn't grow up in a noble family,
but I do know the importance of gratitude.
I'm taken care of by you in this home.
As your daughter,
of course I want what's best for you.
Therefore,
I won't touch the man
Second Sister is in love with.
That is one reason.
The second being...
that I have someone else I love.
So how could I
have any feelings for the marquis's son?
Child,
who is the person you love?
What's there
to be confused about?
Who else could it be?
Qingyuan,
do you really have
zero feelings for the marquis's son?
If so,
you don't have to go to
tomorrow's southern opera.
Stay at home.
You can help me massage my legs.
Yes, Old Madam hasn't been feeling well.
It'd be great if you stay
and nurse her back to health.
Yes,
I'm willing to stay home
and serve you, Grandmother.
Is that so?
Then it's settled.
Yan Rui is nothing
but a short-lived nuisance
who won't last long.
He's even made an enemy
of our Xie family.
Are you really willing to give up
the marquis's son for him?
I...
Even if the marquis's son is fond of me,
how could I dare to
compete with Second Sister?
The mascot
and the blood-written poem...
were that girl's scheme?
You haven't been with our family
for long,
and I haven't had the chance to
pass any wisdom down to you.
Today, allow me to tell you
about your father.
Twenty years ago,
Shu was
just a petty official.
He got to where he is today
not by keeping the peace
and always yielding,
but by
fighting his way through a situation
with wolves at the front
and tigers at the back.
He fought with tigers and snakes.
He snatched food from wolves.
He climbed the political ladder
the hard way,
navigating a bloody
and brutal competition.
Sailing against the current,
you fall back if you don't advance.
Now that you're a part of the Xie family,
you should know that we're different
from those centuries-old noble families.
Our family fought hard
to get where we are today.
The only way to
eliminate disrespect
is to fight back.